やっ、やめてくれぇ！
Please, no!
お…おらを食わんでくれぇ！
Please don't eat me!
Party is over
But I still wanna dance
I can't even sleep
Someday, one day my passion's fire will
From the beginning I knew
One day the flames would die out
Hey, I thought I didn't need anything
But even now, I'm so serious
Ah... I still have time to make it
Ah... but I'm gonna burn it up, baby
Sorry darling, it's not that easy
But surely it's not that bad either
Give me fire
Light it up, baby.
I'm gonna burn it up, yeah
Party is over
Sorry darling Hurry up
Ah... I still have time to make it
Give me fire
Light it up, baby.
I'm gonna burn it up, yeah
#10 The story of Tahomaru
There hasn't been any rain
for 2 months now.
もうふた月以上も雨が降っておりませぬ
If this drought continues,
it will affect the harvest.
れ以上続けば、収穫にも差し響きましょう
The neighboring Asakura clan
is getting restless.
殿。隣国の朝倉に不審な動きが。
We've gotten news that they've been
quietly gathering an army at the border.
にらみ合いが続く国境の町に密かに兵を
集めているとの知らせが入っております。
We should take action
before they start a war.
軍を興される前に、こちらから動くべきかと
That grave face...
あのただならぬ様子…
It must be related to the secret
Father is keeping from me.
やはりあれこそ、父上たちが隠されていることでは
Mutsu, Hyogo.
陸奥。兵庫。
I need you to do something.
やってもらいたいことがある。
Don't let anyone from my family know.
ただし、家の者には知られるな
"HALL OF HELL"
It must be that baby.
あの赤子だな？
He's still alive and is trying
to take his body back from you.
あやつが生きて、貴様らに奪われた体を取り戻さんとしている
Answer me!
答えよ
Just as I thought...
やはり…
You done?
終わったか？
You okay?
あにき…？
Oh, jeez.
あちゃー…
Anyways, that merchant says
that the land is really rich there.
でな。その商人のおっさんが言うには、
とにかく土地が豊かなんだって。
The people eat all the white rice
they want even in these times.
このご時世にみーんな白い飯を腹いっぱい食ってんだってよ
Amazing, huh?
な？すごいだろ？
Let's go there next. We'll make
loads of money and stuff ourselves silly.
次はそこに決まりだな。がっぽり稼いでいいもんたらふく食うんだ。
Whole sea breams, dried abalones,
manju steamed buns...
鯛のお頭焼きに、干しアワビにまんじゅうに…
Manju?
マンジュ？
They're soft, sweet, and so delicious.
やわっこくて甘くて、とびっきり旨い食いモンだよ！
You'll love them, just you wait.
まっ、楽しみにしときなって！
I'd been wanting to ask you.
あぁ…そういやぁ、前から気になってたんだけど…
It's a family seal on that amulet, right?
Is it your family's?
そのお守りの模様、そりゃ家紋だよな。兄貴の家のか？
I've drugged him.
薬を使いました。
He'll answer anything you ask him.
どのようなことでも答えるでしょう
My father has given you
special orders, hasn't he?
父上から特別な命を申し付かっているな
What were those orders?
何を命じられた
To find a baby
that disappeared 16 years ago...
16年前に消えた…赤子と…
and the midwife.
産婆を探せ…と…
Why is my father looking for a baby?
赤子だと？なぜ父親はその赤子を探す
Because...
それは…
Answer me.
答えよ
He tried to bite his tongue off.
舌を噛み切ろうとしたようです
Will he die?
助からぬか？
No, the cut is not deep.
いえ…傷は浅くにとどまっております
The drug must've weakened him.
薬で力が入らなかったのでしょう
Father, what is on your mind?
父上。何をお考えですか
The Asakura clan is getting restless.
朝倉が不穏な動きを見せておる
Is that all?
それだけですか。
Father, why are you searching for a baby?
父上、なぜ赤子などお探しになられているのです。
A baby from over a decade ago.
それも10年以上も前の
That headless Goddess of Mercy
that Mother worships,
母が拝む首のない菩薩像。
does it have anything to do with it?
あれと関わりがあるのではありませんか？
Please answer me, Father!
お答えください。父上！
It is none of your concern.
お前は知らずともよい！
-Yet...
-End of story.
あ…ですが…
二度は言わぬ
How can you still be alive?
なぜ生きていた…
I'm surprised you found me here.
よくここが分かったな
You always came here as a child
whenever anything happened.
幼少の頃は、何かあるとこの場所で
And we came for you each time.
そのたびにこうして迎えに来た。
Every time.
いつだって
Young Master.
若
Let's go home.
帰りましょう
When I was a child, huh.
幼少の頃か…
I must still seem like a child
to my father.
父上には、今も私が幼な子に見えるのだろう。
That's why he won't take me to war
and keeps secrets.
だから戦にも出さぬし、隠し事もなさる
I've never seen my father
looking like that.
父上のあのような顔、初めて見たわ
The matter with the baby
must mean that much to him.
赤子の件とは、それほどの大事か…
What's going on?
何だ？
Please, have mercy on us.
お願いしますだ、どうかご慈悲を
Don't just leave us here to die!
おらたちを見捨てんでくだせぇ
Let go of me! Let go, or I'll...
えぇーい！貴様ら離さぬか！手をどけねば…
What's going on?
何事だ
Sir Tahomaru.
多宝丸様
We were passing through this village
on our way back.
え…屋敷へ戻ろうとこの村を通りかかった折、
They suddenly stopped us.
この者たちが突然
Please, save us!
どうか…おらたちをお助けくだせぇ！
The whole village is going to be
eaten up by the monster.
このままじゃ、村の者みんな化け物に食われちまいます！
Monster, you say?
化け物だと！？
A whirling current?
渦潮？
Ripples in the water
suddenly turn into a whirling current.
湖面にさざ波が当たったと思ったら、突然渦潮に変わりやして…
The current pulls you in,
and there's a huge mouth waiting here.
それで、渦に引き寄せられてくと、
まるで人の口みたいなもんが待ち構えとるんです…！
And it eats up our people, boat and all.
そいつが船ごと人を飲み込んです…！
Many of our villagers
have fallen victim to it.
もう何人も村のもんが犠牲になっております
A whirling current with a mouth...
渦潮に人の口か…
It does sound like the supernatural.
確かに魑魅魍魎の類だな。
Fine, I will defeat it for you.
よかろう。私がその化け物を退治してくれる
Sir Tahomaru.
多宝丸様。
You don't believe these people, do you?
この者たちの話を信じるおつもりですか？
Even if it were true,
you shouldn't be fighting monsters...
よしんば真であったとしても、化け物退治など…
These people are not lying.
この者たちの言葉に嘘はない。
My people are suffering.
You tell me to leave them?
民が苦しんでいるのに、放っておけと申すか！
No, that is not what I meant...
い、いえ、そのような…
If the monster scares you,
go ahead and leave.
化け物に臆したのなら、お前たちだけ帰ればよい！
Sir Tahomaru!
多宝丸様
You don't have to come, either.
お前たちも怖ければ来なくてよいぞ
You must be joking, sir.
ご冗談でございましょう
We would follow you
even into the depths of hell.
うん！若が行くなら、地獄にだってついていく
What is it?
どうした
The oar seems to be stuck...
それが…櫓が動かねんでさぁ
It's coming.
来る！
There it is! The monster!
でっ…出たぁ！バケモンだぁ！
It's going to eat us...
くっ…食われちまう！
Stay calm, pull the ropes!
うろたえるな！綱を引け！
What's wrong? You can't eat us
just by waiting there.
どうした。そこでじっとしていては、こちらを食うことはかなわんぞ！
It's a crab! A monster crab!
か、カニだ！バケモンガニだ！
What a hideous sight.
なんと醜悪な姿よ…
I will slay you.
今すぐ叩き斬ってくれる！
Young Master!
若！
It got away.
逃げた？
It's attacking from below.
ヤツめ！水中から！
Sir Tahomaru!
多宝丸様！
Pull the ropes, get back on land!
綱を引け！丘に上がる！
It's been hurt badly, too.
相手も傷、軽くない…
It can't come chasing us.
だから追ってこれない…
If it had stabbed a few more times,
the boat would've sunk.
あと数度突かれていたら、船が持ちませんでした
It is disadvantageous for us
to fight on the lake.
やはり船上での戦いはこちらが不利かと
What should we do?
どうする、若
Young Master, a word.
若。畏れながら…
The monster eats with its mouth.
あやつも獲物を口で食らいまする。
We should carry explosives in our clothes
and make them explode as he swallows us.
あらかじめ懐に火薬を忍ばせ、飲まれた際炸裂させるのです。
It has a hard shell, but a soft inside.
外は固くとも内は脆い。
The monster will definitely be killed.
必ずや化け物を殺せましょう
So the one who is swallowed
will die with the monster, huh.
飲まれた者もろともな。化け物と心中か
We will do it.
俺たちがやる！
I just said it'd kill you.
死ぬと言ったのだぞ！
It will not.
死なない！
We brothers only exist to protect you.
俺たち兄弟は、若を守るためにいる。
If we died, we couldn't do that.
死んだら若を守れない。
So we will not die.
だから死なない！
Young Master.
若…
Look at this land.
見よ。この景色を
The mountains are green,
and the streams are flowing.
山は緑が濃く
泉は水に溢れ
The paddies are full of rice.
水田は稲で満ちている
This is Daigo's land.
これが醍醐の土地だ。
But I heard it wasn't like this
before I was born.
だが…私が生まれる前は違ったと聞く
Floods kept the rice from growing.
水害によって稲は育たず
People chewed on tree roots
to keep from starving.
木の根を噛んで日々の飢えを凌ぐほどだったと
And who made this land so rich?
それをここまで立て直したのは誰か。
My father, Daigo Kagemitsu.
我が父、醍醐景光だ！
I am his son, Tahomaru.
私はその息子、多宝丸！
I will defeat any measly monster
with my own hands.
化け物ごとき、この手で必ずや討ち果たしてみせよう！
What I need you to do is not to die.
お前たちがすべきは、死ぬことではない。
Just trust me. That's all I ask.
私を信じる、ただそれだけで良い
Young Master.
若…
Yes, sir!
はっ！
Hyogo, lift me up.
兵庫！私を担ぎ上げろ！
Hurry.
早く！
Higher, even higher.
もっとだ！もっと高く！
That's it.
そうか…
Mutsu, gather everyone up.
陸奥！皆を集めろ！
This is our only way to defeat it.
これしかヤツを討つ手立てはない。
It won't be easy.
容易いことではないが…
I'll need your help.
やってくれるな？
We've been waiting for you.
現れたな、化け物め！
Open the sluice!
水門を開け！
There are many small lakes
along the main lake.
湖の脇にはいくつもの小さな湖が点在しておる
We connected one with a sluice,
with another sluice for draining.
その一つを水門で繋げ…別の水門から水を抜けば
And there you have it.
このとおり…
I see you now. I will slay you this time!
姿を現しおったな！今度こそ斬ってくれる！
You all stand back.
お前たちは退がっていろ！
Come, Mutsu, Hyogo.
来い、陸奥！兵庫！
-They're subduing that monster...
-Wow...
あんな恐ろしいバケモンを一方的に…
すげぇ…
Sir Tahomaru,
make it pay for what it's done!
多宝丸様ー！おらたちのカタキを取ってくだせぇ！
Sir Tahomaru!
多宝丸様ー！
Hurray for Sir Tahomaru!
Take this, you monster!
ちくしょう、バケモンめ！
Go back to hell!
とっととくたばっちまえ！
This is it for you.
これまでだな…
Let me end your misery.
今楽にしてやる！
Guard the sluice!
水門を守れ！
Hyogo!
兵庫！
I'm coming.
待っていろ…！
-Young Master.
-Sir.
若
Who are you...?
お前は…？
Sorrow scatters in the wind,
piling up to form shadows
Our footsteps admonish
indifference in such verbose ways
As I peek into your fathomless eyes,
I lose my composure
Is there any hope
in the place I am heading to?
I feign amusement and laugh
because this road is so dark
I will be there to shine the light
I'm used to playing at saying goodbye,
but I cried when I waved to you
Our fiery woes fade... and fade...
until night falls upon us
If I knew tomorrow would be so mundane,
I wouldn't have said that I wanted to live
I know it's futile but can't help dreaming
of a future... a future... you are to blame
"Bakemonogani"